# SARAH HUMPHREY

#### Knoxville,TN

Phone: (304) 731-8669 | Email: sarahhumphrey2016@outlook.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-humphrey-data-analyst

| GitHub: https://github.com/shumph10 |

Portfolio: <a href="https://sarahhumphreyportfolio.herokuapp.com/">https://sarahhumphreyportfolio.herokuapp.com/</a>

## Summary

Driven Data Analyst with background in Mathematics. Gained a Certificate from Vanderbilt University's Data Analytics and Visualization Bootcamp. Versed in collaborative and independent research, development, implementation, and communication, prioritizing excellent but efficient results with raw or cleaned data.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: Python, SQL, R,

Tools: Postgres, Flask, Matplotlib, Tableau, AWS, Spark, Google Colab

Databases: SQL, SQLite, MongoDB

### **Projects**

#### HUD Housing Assistance Analysis | https://github.com/shumph10/Housing\_Assistance\_Analysis

- Use of HUD data to establish factors for increase in strain on governmental housing assistance programs since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic using machine learning.
- Tools/Languages used: Python, JavaScript, HTML, VS Code, Tableau, Google CoLab

#### World Weather Analysis | https://github.com/shumph10/World\_Weather\_Analysis

- Use of Python and pandas to generate random cities and query OpenWeatherMap API for destination temperatures, filtering and creating GMaps figures by user input.
- Tools / languages used: Python, Pandas, Jupyter Notebooks, OpenWeatherMaps API, Google Maps API

#### Pewlett Hackard Analysis | https://github.com/shumph10/Pewlett-Hackard-Analysis

- Creation of SQL database to parse company's data and establish number of employees nearing retirement, creation of potential solutions to ease transition.
- Tools / languages used: Quick DBD, SQL, Postgres, PgAdmin

# **Experience**

Manager, Bartender

**2020 - Current** 

Admiral Pub Knoxville, TN

Relay of customer purchasing data for presentation to owner and team member, informing business and purchasing decisions. Communication with patrons to design and schedule

marketing opportunities, resulting in establishment of rewards programs and scheduled activities to increase customer outreach, participation, and retention.

Key Accomplishments:

• Establishment and expansion of reward programs and weekly promotions through customer outreach. Loyalty program participation increased by 11% over the past year.

Bartender 2017 – Current

Copper Cellar Co.

Responsible for customer satisfaction, delivery of consistent product and quality control. Team leader for training new members with emphasis on member retention and job satisfaction. Continual contact with new members to ensure satisfaction and relay concerns to upper management.

Key Accomplishments:

- Best liquor counts in the company, out of approximately 30 stores, for 15 consecutive months. This qualitatively defined success of product control regulation.
- Assisted in development of a detailed day by day training program policies for new team members, that has been utilized for 3 years.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

2017 - 2018

Knoxville, TN

#### **University of Tennessee**

Knoxville, TN

Assisting lead professors with key steps in protein analysis for research success, with detailed process reports for improvement and consistency of practices and aid in further research design.

#### **Undergraduate Teaching Assistant**

2017 - 2019

#### **University of Tennessee**

Knoxville, TN

Design and instruction of classes for biology and first year students. Production of detailed class plans and experimental design with emphasis on core ideas student participation. Ensured retention and understanding through feedback on written and oral communications.

#### **Education**

**Data Analytics Boot Camp Certificate:** Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning. Emphasis on project production, written communication of results and visualizations, and classmate collaboration.

**Bachelors of Science, Biochemical, Cellular, & Molecular Biology:** University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN

Graduated with Cum Laude honors in December, 2019, GPA 3.59. Taught multiple courses for first year and laboratory students. Participated in undergraduate research with focus in medicine digestion rates and establishment of cofactors for consistent digestion across patients.